Era of Warring States
（柱間）ま　待ってくれ。
W-Wait...
（柱間）ほ　本当に
うちは一族なのか？
A-Are you sure he's an Uchiha?
そうだ　お前が千手だと　バレれば→
Yes...
If he's found out that you're Senju,
こちらの情報を盗むために
気を許した振りをする。
he'll pretend to let his guard down
to steal intel on us.
Do not trust him.
信用するな。
（柱間）いや　あいつは　そんな…。
No, he's not like that...
お前は　弟の仇の一族を
信じるのか？
You'd trust the clan who killed
your younger brother?
あの少年も　腹では
何を考えておるか→
You have no idea what
he's thinking inside his gut!
わかったものではない。
もし　騙されれば→
If he tricks you, you'll be putting
the entire Senju Clan at risk.
千手の皆を
危険に陥れることになる。
そんな…。
That's not...
Just in case, Tobirama and I
will come along. Understood?
念のために　わしと扉間も付く。
わかったな！
返事は？
Answer me!
わかった。
Yes.
（マダラ）早速だがよ→
I know it's right off the bat,
but how about we just skip stones
instead of exchanging greetings?
まずは　挨拶代わりの
水切りからいくか。
（柱間）おう。
Yeah...
（２人）はっ！
柱間　わりぃ　今日ダメだ。
Hashirama...
Sorry. I can't stay today...
急な用を思い出してよ。
I just remembered something
I have to do.
そ　そうか。　じゃあ　俺も→
O-Oh yeah?
I'm going to head home then.
今日は　帰るとするぞ。
RUN
TRAP, SCRAM
このスピード　逃げきる気か！
That speed!
He's planning to run for it!
柱間め　教えたな！
Damn Hashirama!
He warned him!
行くぞ　扉間。
（扉間）はい。
Let's go, Tobirama!
Yes!
考えることは　同じようですね。
Seems like we're both
on the same page.
千手仏間。
それと　扉間だったか。
Butsuma Senju.
And Tobirama, I believe.
のようだな　うちはタジマ。
それから　イズナだな。
Indeed, Tajima Uchiha.
And Izuna, right?
＜柱間：偶然にも　うちは側も→
It seemed the Uchiha coincidentally
had the same idea.
同じ考えだったようだ。
まったく　同じ状況。
Exactly the same circumstances.
千手仏間と　うちはタジマは
ほぼ同じ力だということが→
Butsuma Senju and Tajima Uchiha
both knew from numerous prior clashes
that they possessed
practically equal strength.
互いに　幾たびかの戦いで
わかっていた＞
（２人）やめろ！
- Stop!
＜忍は　何があろうと→
Shinobi are trained to keep
their hearts in check on the battlefield,
戦場で　心を乱さぬよう
訓練される。
no matter what happens.
一瞬の心の乱れが　隙を生じ→
A single flash of emotional display
can lead to vulnerability
and mean the difference
between life and death.
それが　生死を分ける。
だが
大人の２人は　わかっているのだ。
However...
The two adults were well aware...
目の前で　我が子が殺されれば
ほんのわずかだが→
that if their own child were killed
right before their eyes,
it would likely, no matter how slight,
unbalance their heart.
己の心に
乱れが生じるであろうことを。
つまり　どちらが先手を取るかで
勝負が決まることを＞
Meaning...
whoever could land the first strike
would determine the outcome.
（２人）あっ！
TRAP, SCRAM              RUN
弟を傷つけようとするやつは
誰だろうと許せねえ！
I'll never forgive anyone who tries
to hurt my little brother,
no matter who they are!
それは　俺も同じだ！
Same here!
（マダラ）柱間よ。
なんぞ。
Hey, Hashirama...
What is it?
（マダラ）俺たちの言ってた
バカみてえな絵そらごとには→
Maybe it just isn't possible for us...
しょせん…。
to reach that...
（マダラ）届かねえのかもな。
pipe dream of ours...
マダラ　お前…。
Madara... What are you...?
少しの間だったが
楽しかったぜ…　柱間。
It may have been brief,
but it was fun...Hashirama.
３対３か　どうだ　行けるか？　マダラ。
Three against three...
Can we take them, Madara?
いや　柱間は俺より強い。
No...
Hashirama is stronger than me.
このままやれば　こっちが負ける。
If we fight, we'll lose.
兄さんより強い子供が？
There's a kid stronger than you, Brother?
I see, quite impressive.
そうか　それほどとはな…
引くぞ！
Let's retreat!
じゃあな。
So long.
Madara!
マダラ！　お前　ほんとは
諦めちゃいねえよな？
You...really haven't given up, have you?
お前は　やっと俺と同じ…。
You've gotten to the same point I...
お前は千手。
You are Senju.
できれば　違ってほしかった…。
I truly wish it wasn't so.
俺の兄弟は　千手に殺された。
My brothers were killed
by the Senju.
（マダラ）そして　お前の兄弟は
うちはに…。
And your brothers, by the Uchiha...
So there's no need to show
our guts to each other.
（マダラ）だからさ　お互いはらわたは
見せる必要もねえだろ。
（マダラ）次からは　戦場で会うことに
なるだろうぜ…　千手柱間。
Our next meeting will likely be
on the battlefield...
Hashirama Senju.
俺は…　うちはマダラだ。
I'm...Madara Uchiha.
見て　父様　兄さんの眼。
Father! Look at Big Brother's eyes!
フフッ　千手の情報は
入らなかったが→
We may not have obtained
any intel on the Senju...
代わりに　いいものを
こちらは手に入れられたようだ。
but it seems we gained something
valuable from this, after all.
写輪眼…　今　開眼したのか？
He awakened his Sharingan...just now?
＜柱間：そのとき　写輪眼の開眼が
何を意味するか→
In that moment,
I felt like I understood what awakening
the Sharingan truly signified.
俺には　わかった気がした＞
＜　やつは　友となった俺を
完全に消すことにしたのだ＞
He decided to completely
erase his friend.
To erase me from his life.
＜　それから俺たちは　戦った。
After that, we battled.
We fought each other day after day.
来る日も　来る日も戦い続け→
気づけば　俺たちは
互いに一族の長になり…＞
And before we knew it,
we'd each become
our respective clan's leaders.
＜成し遂げたかった夢から
いちばん遠いところにいた＞
We were at the furthest place possible...
from the dream that
we wanted to fulfill.
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
ハァ　ハァ…。
火遁　豪火球の術！
Fire Style!
Fire Ball Jutsu!
水遁　水龍弾の術！
Water Style!
Water Dragon Missile!
《闇雲に攻撃か。
写輪眼を持たぬ不幸を呪うが…》
A blind attack...
I curse the misfortune of the ones
who do not have the Sharingan.
飛雷神斬り！
Flying Raijin Slice!
イズナ！
Izuna!
しっかりしろ。　必ず助ける。
Hang in there!
I swear I'll save you!
ハァ　ハァ…。
クッ。
柱間。
Hashirama...
マダラ　お前は俺には勝てない。
Madara... You cannot defeat me.
＜　だが俺は
夢を捨てきれないでいた＞
But I had never abandoned our dream.
もう　終わりにしよう。
Why don't we end this?
忍最強のうちはと千手が
手を組めば→
If the two strongest shinobi clans,
the Uchiha and Senju, join forces,
国も我々と見合う
他の一族を見つけられなくなる。
nations will not be able to find
other shinobi clans that
can stand against us...
いずれ争いも鎮静化していく。
さあ。
The conflict will eventually
start to die down.
Come on.
ダメだ　兄さん！
イズナ！
No... Big Brother...
Izuna!
やつらに騙されるな。
イズナ。
Do not be deceived by them...
Izuna!
みんな　うちはは→
Have you forgotten that
these bastards killed everyone...
こいつら一族に殺されたのを
忘れたの？
killed the Uchiha?
＜戦いは　うちは一族が
劣勢なのは→
It was clear to all that the Uchiha Clan
was in an unfavorable position.
誰の目にも明らかだった。
後　千手へ亡命する者まで
現れはじめた＞
In fact, defectors to the Senju
soon began showing up.
＜　そして　その頃
マダラも変わったのだ＞
And that's about when
Madara changed as well.
＜永遠の万華鏡写輪眼を
手に入れてな＞
He had obtained
the Eternal Mangekyo Sharingan.
その眼…。
イズナはどうした？
Those eyes...
What happened to Izuna?
この前の傷がもとで弟は死んだ。
My little brother ended up dying
from that day's wounds...
うちはを守るために
俺に力を残して。
Leaving me powers that
will help protect the Uchiha!
休戦協定の書状を送ったはずだ。
I sent you a cease-fire agreement!
うちはを守るなら
もうこんな戦いはやめようぞ。
If you truly want to protect the Uchiha,
let's stop fighting!
柱間！
Hashirama!
木遁　花樹界降臨！
Wood Style, Deep Forest Bloom!
クッ　花粉の毒か。
Poison Pollen eh?
（柱間）やめろマダラ。
Enough, Madara!
もう戦いは無意味だ。
Fighting is meaningless!
無意味だと？
Meaningless?
だったら　なぜ　イズナは死んだ。
Then why did Izuna die?
（マダラ）貴様たちが→
It's because....
because you bastards killed him!
貴様たちが殺したからだ！
木人の術！
Wood Golem Jutsu!
柱間！
Hashirama!
うお～！
フン！
うおっ。
マダラ　俺たちは友達だった。
Madara, we were friends!
そして同じ夢を見た。
And we shared the same dream!
柱間　いつまで
ガキのようなことを言っている。
Hashirama!
How long will you keep saying
such juvenile things?
（マダラ）はらわたを
見せ合うことなんて→
It's just not possible to show
our guts to each other!
できやしねえのさ。
Don't you get it?
Hashirama!
柱間！
マダラ！
Madara!
＜一日続いた戦いの末→
At the end of a battle
that lasted a whole day...
Madara's back touched
the ground for the very first time.
マダラは初めて地面に背をつけた＞
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
Madara...
マダラ　終わりだ。
You're finished.
待て　扉間。
Wait, Tobirama.
なぜだ兄者　今がチャンスだろ。
Why, Elder Brother?!
This is our chance!
手出しは許さん。
No one touches him!
フッ　いっそ　ひと思いにやれ　柱間。
Just get it over with, Hashirama.
お前にやられるなら　本望だ。
It would be an honor to die
by your hand.
（柱間）かっこつけても　無駄ぞ。
Stop posturing.
長であるお前をやれば→
If I kill the clan leader of the Uchiha,
it will only incite the young ones
who follow you.
お前を慕う若いうちはの者が
また暴れだす。
もう　そんな芯のあるやつは
いねえよ　うちはには。
There isn't anyone left with such pluck
among the Uchiha anymore.
（柱間）いや　必ずいる。
Sure there are.
たとえ　今はいなくても
いずれ出てくる。
Perhaps not right now, but in time.
なあ　もう　こんな戦いは
終わりにしないか？
Come on...
Why don't we end this war?
（柱間）俺たちは
約束したじゃないか。
We made a promise, remember?
いつか理想の里をつくるって。
To create the ideal village someday.
また　昔みてえに
水切りできねえか？　一緒に。
Can't we go back to those days...
and skip rocks together?
そりゃ無理ってもんだぜ。
That's just impossible.
俺とお前は　もう同じじゃねえ。
You and I are no longer the same.
((柱間：ここに
俺たちの集落をつくろう。
Let's build our settlement here!
あっ　そんなバカなこと言ってんの
お前くらいだぞ。
Heh... You're pretty much the only one
spouting such nonsense.
お前は　どうなんだよ？
Well then, what about you?
ああ　その集落　つくったら→
Yeah... If that settlement gets built here,
then I could watch over
my little brother,
今度こそ弟を→
(一望できる　ここから
しっかり守ってやる))
and protect him in this place
where you can see to no end!
今の俺には　もう→
I don't have a single brother left.
兄弟は　１人もいねえ。
守るものは　何にもねえ。
I have nothing to protect.
それに　お前らを信用できねえ。
And...I just can't trust you.
どうすれば
俺たちを信用してもらえる？
Is there any way I can
convince you to trust us?
Well, there is a way to
show each other our guts...
（マダラ）俺たちが　はらわたを
見せ合えるとすりゃ→
今　お前が弟を殺すか→
Either kill your brother...
己が自害してみせるか。
or kill yourself right now.
それで　あいこだ。
And then we'll be even.
I'd be willing to trust your clan.
そうすりゃ
お前ら一族を信じてやる。
弟を殺すか　自害しろだと？
Kill your little brother or kill yourself?
ふざけたこと
言ってんじゃねえぞ　この…。
How dare you say
something so ridicu-
I agree.
俺も同意見だ。
言ってることがむちゃくちゃだ。
This is crazy!
どうするんだ？　兄者。
So what are you going
to do, Elder Brother?
この俺を殺すのか？
Are you going to kill me now?
それとも　こんなやつの
たわ言のために死ぬのか？
Or are you going to die on account
of this guy's nonsense?
バカバカしい　耳を貸すな兄者。
It's idiotic. Don't listen to him!
ありがとう　マダラ。
Thank you, Madara.
お前は　やっぱり情の深いやつだ。
You really are kindhearted.
Madara had given me a choice,
＜マダラは　ちゃんと
選択肢をくれたのだ。
弟を殺さないでいい選択肢を。
an option where I wouldn't have
to kill my little brother.
やつも　わかっていた。
He knew all too well...
how an older brother feels
towards his younger siblings.
弟を持つ兄としての心の内を＞
（柱間）いいか　扉間。
Listen, Tobirama...
俺の最後の言葉として
しっかり心に刻め。
Etch these words into your heart,
for these are my final words...
兄者。
Brother...
Words that I shall be exchanging
with my life.
（柱間）俺の命に代える言葉だ。
You too, my fellow clan members.
一族の皆も同様だ。
俺の死後　決してマダラを殺すな。
After my death, do not kill Madara.
今後　うちはと千手は
争うことを許さぬ。
I forbid any fighting between
the Uchiha and Senju.
皆の父と
まだ見ぬ孫たちにかけて誓え。
Swear this right now...
upon the lives of your fathers,
and your grandchildren yet unborn.
さらばだ。
Farewell...
もう　いい。
Enough...
お前のはらわたは見えた。
I have now seen your guts.
＜夢のようだった。
It was like a dream...
うちはと千手が手を組んだのだ。
The Uchiha and the Senju
formed an alliance.
There would no longer
be any casualties,
もう多くの犠牲が出ることもない。
nor would any more children
have to die.
多くの子供の死もなくなる＞
＜　そして　俺たちは
里づくりを始めた＞
And so, we began building our village.
Do you remember how we used
to talk here when we were brats?
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では　最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華な歌手の
皆さんによる→
華麗なステージをお届けいたします。